# Siddharth Maurya

South West Delhi, Delhi, India



linkedin.com/in/siddharth-maurya



sidmaurya@gmail.com



+91 7042741114

### Summary

An Indian Air Force Veteran having taken voluntary retirement as Group Captain (equivalent to Colonel) has 24 years of rich experience of team building, people management, behavior change management, human resource aspects, and administration. Presently, State Lead of a Leadership Development Program in 2 states improving the present Indian education set up in government schools. Two years of experience in Operations Management in the social development domain along with the implementation of a 2 years long fellowship program. Played a decisive role in developing teams and building leadership at all levels. As State Lead, owns valuable expertise in annual budget preparation, financial management of the operations, operational planning/execution, managing donors/fund houses, and team management. Proven leader with accomplished high credibility and good communication skills.

#### Experience

#### ▶ ► Programme Director

Kaivalya Education Foundation

May 2018 - Present (2 years 1 month +)

Managed large teams, executed operations with a field-level strategy, ensured quality mentoring for about 120 fellows every year, oversaw multiple stakeholders including government and governed a budget of about Rs 100 Cr spread across in Rajasthan and Uttarakhand.

# ■ Joint Director (Security) South Block MoD

Ministry of Defence of India

Apr 2015 - Apr 2018 (3 years 1 month)

As Senior Executive at Tri services Headquarters at Ministry of Defence, South Block, New Delhi responsible for the security and safety of sensitive government premises of the highest politico-military leadership.

# Commanding Officer close equivalent of Head of a Business Unit

**Indian Air Force** 

Mar 2013 - Apr 2015 (2 years 2 months)

Commanded IAF Police Headquarters at Meghalaya looking after discipline, Counter Intelligence, Security, and Police liaison for protocol matters of 4 North Eastern States.

# **Joint Director UAV Operations**

Indian Air Force

Dec 2000 - Oct 2013 (12 years 11 months)

As Senior Executive led and managed a team of UAV Sensor operators and pilots for the conduct of the extensive state of the art Unmanned flying Operations across the whole of India.

# Operations Manager

Indian Air Force

Jun 1996 - Dec 2000 (4 years 7 months)

Managed Air Defence operations in Rajasthan, Punjab, Gujarat and Jammu & Kashmir keeping a vigil against any external or internal threat.

#### **Education**

#### Indian Institute of Management Ahmedabad

Business Management, Business Administration, Management and Operations 2017 - 2018

6 months in-campus Certificate program in Business Management for Armed Forces specially selected by IIM Ahmedabad.

#### Symbiosis Institute of Business Management, Pune

Master's degree, Human Resources Management/Personnel Administration, General 2002 - 2003

#### Defence Services Staff College, Wellington

Master of Science (M.Sc.), Def and Strategic Studies 2011 - 2012

A highly prestigious Program with meritorious attendees including 30 plus international military officers of various countries specializing in International Relations and Defence Strategic Studies.



#### Kennesaw State University

Certificate, Cyber Security and its Ten Domains Offered by Cousera



#### 🐌 St. Joseph's Academy, Dehradun

ISC, Science

#### **Honors & Awards**



#### Commendation by Chief of Air Staff, Indian Air Force - Chief of Air Staff

Oct 2009

For conducting successful UAV counter-insurgency& intelligence operations pan India



### 📃 Commendation by Air Officer Commanding in Chief, Western Air Command, Indian Air

Force - Western Air Command, Indian Air Force

Jan 2004

For contribution in setting up of new establishments worth Rs 200 crore.

#### Skills

Program Management • Project Implementation • Strategy • Aerospace • Human Resources (HR) • Training • UAV Sensor Operator & Pilot • Remote Sensing • Security & Policing • Leadership Development